[Blood River]
[Based on the novel of the same name from Zhou Munan's Youth in Jianghu series]
[Available on fanqienovel.com & bkneng.com]
[Episode 34]
Tang Lianyue!
Don't touch him!
That was too dangerous.
Our opponents are tough.
We should retreat for now.
- But... - Let's go!
You were hit by his Poison Palm.
Even if you're the Xuanwu Guardian,
there's no way you can resume the fight.
Let's retreat for now.
We'll think of something later.
Xuanwu Guardian of Tianqi City...
He's extraordinary indeed.
He would've taken my life
if you guys were one step later.
Don't you agree?
You would've died long ago
had he used his hidden weapons.
If so, why didn't he use them?
Tang Lianyue is very intelligent.
He found out about the identities
of the people here.
He guessed that we came here
to deal with Prince of Langya.
If he killed any of us
and left his hidden weapons here during the process,
perhaps
it would become an indication
that he was after Prince of Langya.
What should we do with them, then?
Everyone,
please leave for now.
I'll send my men to notify you all
about the new gathering spot later.
Let's hurry.
Prince of Langya.
Master Su.
Master Su, please don't worry.
No one tracked me on my way here.
No one would know
that you guys are here.
Your Highness, your mentor is Mr. Li of the Academy.
You were renowned for
your martial arts long ago.
I have no cause to worry about.
Your Highness, people once called you
the Elegant Gentleman.
Your wits and intellect are second to none.
And, your cunningness knows no bounds.
Indeed.
You were only willing to put your complete trust in me
after I risked my life in our duel.
Within Tianqi City,
even a person
like me
has to walk every step
as if I'm walking on thin ice.
Therefore,
I can't afford to make mistakes.
Master Su,
I'm sorry.
I heard from Second Master
that the situation at Nanjue was critical.
Guardian Azure Dragon and the elite soldiers under your rule
have already gone there to assist them.
Guardian White Tiger was nowhere to be found.
Guardian Vermilion Bird, Sikong Changfeng,
returned to the martial world many years ago.
Right now,
only Tang Lianyue is assisting you.
This should be
your weakest position
ever since you helped your brother
to obtain the throne.
Master Su,
it seems
you understand the situation here
very well.
Of course, some of them were coincidences.
For example, Lei Mengsha got himself trapped.
However, for some of them,
I suppose you did them on purpose.
You made yourself look weak on purpose.
What are you waiting for?
My opponents
will only strike
when they think I'm weak enough.
And, what I desire
is for them
to strike me.
By then, you'll require my help.
Indeed.
By then,
I'll still be very weak.
I'll be so weak
that I can't even
protect myself.
Therefore, Master Su,
I require your help
for certain matters.
Now that I'm looking at it,
was Blood River's arrival in Tianqi City
a move you planned
long ago?
I cannot plan a move that far ahead.
I was merely following the flow.
However, regarding my promise to you,
I'll definitely
keep it.
All right.
All those who were struck by the puppet poison
were people of Tianqi City
who possessed military strength.
With this leverage,
even if I have no control over them,
they won't dare to act recklessly.
Yong,
I'll tell you this one last time.
Once you make this choice,
there's no turning back.
Uncle,
I never turn back.
For all that you see when you turn back
is unbearable.
Mother!
Mother,
are you okay?
Why are you still doing such needlework?
I'm fine.
It only pricked my finger. I'm not bleeding.
Look.
Your father loves
the needlework I make.
I made him a belt
since I had nothing to do.
And, I made a pair of winter boots for your uncle
and grandfather each.
Come, sit here.
Why are you here today?
Was schoolwork difficult for you?
Not at all.
My teacher even praised me for my intellect.
When Father heard about it,
he granted me a set of scholar's tools.
There's no school today.
That's why I came back to visit you.
Good boy.
Will Father be coming here today?
Perhaps.
Your Highness,
please make a plea on Her Highness's behalf.
Now, His Majesty visits Consort Xuan every day.
It's been so long since he visited us.
You're his first child.
His Majesty doted on you the most in the past.
- You should... - Diancui!
That was unnecessary.
Pay no heed to her words.
Study well
and make me proud.
Your Highness!
Your Highness, we're in trouble!
Your Highness,
there's something wrong with the Ministry of Revenue's accounts,
which were under Lord Dian's supervision.
His Majesty is enraged.
He intends to punish him!
[Dian's Residence]
I suppose your father still has a conscience.
He merely ordered your grandfather to retire.
Perhaps
Father was lenient with him
as Mother belonged to the Dian family.
I suppose he wouldn't bother
to finish off a lone stray dog.
But Yong, don't worry.
I'm joining the military
to fork out a new path
for our family.
I will become your new source of strength.
You must look after your mother
in Tianqi.
Yong,
you're the only kin
I have.
Uncle, you're also
the only blade I can hold
without injuring myself.
Your Highness,
Xuanwu Guardian and the members of Blood River
have headed to Doom Abyss together.
Blood River again?
Su Changhe already agreed to
join hands with us.
Why is Blood River
still obstructing us from executing our plans?
Haoyue.
Go and find Su Changhe.
If he continues to be on his retreat,
our cooperation
will be called off.
By then, we shall
eradicate
every single Blood River member
in Tianqi City.
Yes, Your Highness.
Your Highness.
Why don't you send me there?
After all, if you trace back to our roots,
I suppose I'm a part of them as well.
That'll do.
Besides that,
try to locate
the current hiding spot of Su Muyu and his men.
You may eradicate them
without notifying Su Changhe
when it's necessary.
How did it go?
Yu,
we've already found out about the secret
behind the drugged puppets in Tianqi City.
However, our opponents were too strong.
We had no choice but to retreat.
Yumo and Tang Lianyue
have already returned to Prince of Langya's Manor to report back.
Su Muyu,
we should leave for now.
The situation in Tianqi City is much more complicated than we thought.
I don't think
this is worth it.
Xuewei,
go and ask Changli
about Changhe's retreat.
Yu,
do you intend to give up as well?
I don't want people
to use Blood River as a political tool.
You guys may leave with Miss Bai first.
I'll wait for Changhe's news.
We'll return to Blood River
after I rendezvous with him.
Yu,
you're still the same.
You don't know how to lie at all.
You want us to take Miss Bai with us
while you'll clean up the mess yourself.
I can't afford to leave.
Miss Bai.
Why is that the case?
Tianqi City is facing turmoil
due to the drugged puppets.
And, the puppet spell was developed by
an outcast of Medicine King Valley.
Right now, I have the highest seniority among its members.
I can't just leave without doing anything.
But now,
the Patriarch is on a reclusive retreat.
Master Su
is also heavily wounded.
With our strength,
I'm afraid we won't be able to contribute much
on this battlefield.
Who said so?
Fadog?
Fadog.
Uncle Zhe.
I'm here for you, my girl.
Who actually wounded you?
I'm going to rip him to shreds.
Fadog, you're too late.
Su Muyu
already avenged me.
You brat.
Good job.
Your Highness.
Ms. Yumo, I've long heard of your name.
But this is
our first encounter.
Initially, I wanted to see you
when Blood River came to Tianqi.
It's just that...
It's just
that Lianyue wasn't around back then.
Therefore, there was no need to see me.
Your Highness, you're quite humorous.
Please have a seat.
Thank you, Your Highness.
I came from the Academy.
Back then, Master told us
that being interesting
could attract girls better
than being powerful.
Therefore,
everyone was interesting
in their own way.
Lianyue lived with the Tang Clan since young.
He was
already uninteresting
when he got to know us.
And, I couldn't change him
even after all these years.
Therefore, Ms. Yumo,
I wonder
what you like about him.
I used to like him.
But now,
I no longer like him.
Why is that the case?
He's too timid.
I like bold men.
For example,
a valiant man such as yourself, Your Highness.
Your Highness!
Ms. Yumo,
Lianyue is a good man
whom you can entrust yourself to.
Not me.
Your Highness, what do you mean?
It's because among the men I know,
Lianyue is the only man
who will not change a single bit
when he's sure
that he can
provide you
with a lifetime of happiness,
unless he dies.
Only then
will he dedicate his true feelings to you.
Other people
cannot do so.
Your Highness,
this isn't the time for this.
Master once told me
that discussions of relationship
are suitable
no matter when we initiate the conversation.
The Imperial Assembly will be held soon.
But coincidentally, many of the sons of noblemen
were struck by the puppet poison
at this particular timing.
It's obvious
that First Prince is plotting something.
And, rumors about you have been circulating
around Tianqi City.
I'm sure he's targeting us.
Actually, I think
both have their own merits.
One of them can express his love at any time.
He expresses it in a direct
and carefree manner.
Therefore, it's always ferocious
at the start.
As for the other one, he only expresses his love
after everything has settled down.
It always feels a bit too calm.
Therefore, the beautiful lady has
to endure more hardships.
However,
Lianyue
is a great man.
Your Highness,
what's with the eccentric speech?
It's as if you...
Yumo.
Do not spout nonsense.
You knew what I was going to say, didn't you?
If so, how can that be considered nonsense?
Do you mean
as if I'm telling you my last will?
Perhaps
I am telling you my last will.
Your Highness!
Forget it.
What did you say again?
You said many sons of noblemen
were struck by the puppet poison.
Which family do they come from?
We only managed to identify some of them.
We haven't identified the rest.
Why did you come back, then?
Go and find them.
Find every single one of them.
Protect them all.
After that, figure out a way to neutralize the poison.
But remember,
you must finish these operations
as soon as possible.
If not, things will go south
when their fathers and brothers gather at Tianqi
for the Imperial Assembly.
Perhaps
something worse will happen.
Understood.
Changhe,
are we going to die here?
That won't happen.
I'll surely take you with me
and escape from here.
What about Mother and the rest?
Can we still rescue them?
We can.
Both of us will survive.
Changhe.
Changli?
Are you okay?
Changhe,
you should go.
Just leave me behind.
I'm bleeding so much.
I don't think I can survive!
No.
Just go!
Go!
Changhe!
Just go!
Just leave me behind!
Changhe!
Go!
Changli!
Changhe!
This time,
we're not running away.
Ignorant fool,
it seems you have a death wish.
Who would have the nerve before the King of Hell
to make me face death?
Even the King of Hell
distances himself from me when he sees me!
Finally.
Didn't I already tell you?
Changhe is in a reclusive retreat.
No one is to enter his chamber.
In a reclusive retreat?
Your Patriarch promises to form an alliance with us.
But he disappeared
after making the deal.
And, the rest of Blood River
is obstructing us from executing our plan too.
It's all because
Changhe received a blow from Prince of Langya back then.
He sustained internal injury.
Could it be...
I heard
that every level of the Hell Palm
unveils a new world.
Once one reaches the ninth level,
one can form his own world.
This is my first time
witnessing
a cultivator who has reached the ninth level of Hell Palm.
It's you, old man.
Patriarch of Blood River,
we have met again.
It seems you guys joined First Prince's faction
after leaving Shadow Sect.
I knew I had the right mindset back then.
I should've gotten rid of
all my opponents.
I wonder
if Muyu would regret his decision
if he could see this.
If we wish
to remain in Tianqi for a long time,
we have to find a worthy master to depend on.
His Highness
is quite a good option.
If not,
why would you and I
encounter each other
here?
What do you think?
Now that the deed is over,
the Three Families of Tianqi
and Blood River
are willing to acknowledge you as the Patriarch.
Once His Highness ascends the throne,
we shall replace
the current Inner Security Division
and walk in the sunlight officially.
Let's go.
It's been quite some time since I last met His Highness.
Now that I've reached
the ninth level of Hell Palm,
I wonder who will
be the first
to have a taste of it.
Lianyue was meant to live beneath
the open skies of the martial world.
Does one become more talkative
as they accumulate more life experiences?
You're the same as Sikong Changfeng.
You two like to express your sentiments
while admiring a gorgeous view.
You and I have plucked the same number of flowers and leaves.
But among your harvest,
there are three pieces of peach blossom leaves.
Therefore,
you've lost.
Forget it.
Deliver this message to Sikong Changfeng on my behalf.
I'm going to head to Tianqi.
I'm not sure when I'll return.
I suppose the life I was leading
was too restrained.
That's why I'm feeling sentimental
now that it has come to this.
I suppose a life like yours
is great.
You lead a carefree life.
Your mother sent you here to protect me in secret.
Sorry for the trouble.
So, do you regret the decision you made?
If, one day,
you encounter an expert,
and you have a chance to challenge him to a duel,
but you'll fail and won't be able to wield the sword again
if you challenge him.
Will you regret the fact
that you challenged him to a duel?
I won't.
That is also my answer.
Life is just like the Peach Blossom Coin
used for divination on Mount Wangcheng.
Only one side can face upward.
If I want to lead a serene life,
I have to cast away the carefree martial world life.
If you wish to experience peerless swordsmanship,
you have to bear the consequences of challenging him.
That's frustrating.
What I meant was
I won't lose to him.
If so,
I shall head to Pleasure House first.
Beauty,
I'll go and enjoy your performance again when I'm free.
Sir, I'll surely reserve a good seat
for you.
Boss.
You guys are here as well.
You instructed Patriarch to tell us
that we no longer need to be
the masked Twelve Zodiacs.
But fighting by your side
is something exciting.
Therefore,
we've returned.
Your new blade looks great.
I retrieved this from Yellow Springs Pawnshop.
It cuts through iron like butter.
Boss,
don't worry.
Our martial arts
have improved quite a lot as well.
Could we leave Tianqi City right now
if we didn't listen to that lass?
If it's possible,
Uncle Zhe, I hope you can take Miss Bai with you.
As for the affairs of Tianqi City,
allow Changhe and me to deal with them.
If that's the case,
I don't think it'll work.
Look at your current state.
What do you think you can do?
If you don't want your body
to be riddled with holes, just like mine,
the best way is for you
to stop using martial arts
and rest and recuperate under my daughter's care
for a few months.
Only then will you be able to recover completely.
I'll try to recover as soon as possible.
Uncle Zhe, please don't worry.
How could I?
You and I suffered the same type of injury.
I could tell this at first glance.
The current you is...
If a breeze were to come right now,
you'll dissipate like
the incense smoke.
Uncle Zhe, not only did you survive,
but you also retained
your reign as the top martial artist of Su family.
I know this better than you.
If the current me
has to fight with my all,
if I have to fight with someone on equal terms as I,
I'll surely die from it.
That's the consequence of the grave injury
I sustained back then.
Even Xin Baicao
won't be able to treat my condition.
I wish
to entrust my daughter to you in the future.
Therefore, I don't want you to end up like me.
Uncle Zhe.
I have my own plans.
My foot!
Your final plan
is to forfeit your own life.
If she gets together with someone like you,
she'll become a widow in the end.
But I suppose we don't have a choice.
That's the person you are.
That's why you're Su Muyu.
Since both you and my daughter
have already decided,
let me
do you a favor.
Uncle Zhe, you mustn't.
Why not?
If you use this art,
you'll receive a serious backlash!
Don't worry.
I won't die yet.
I'll live on
so that I can look after my daughter.
Su Muyu.
You don't have a choice.
You have to accept my zhenqi.
If not, I'll die
from exhausting all of my zhenqi.
Su Muyu,
once you overcome this ordeal,
you should leave the martial world.
Leave the martial world?
For example,
you can return to Nan'an City.
You can be a medical apprentice for the rest of your life.
You can help my daughter
to sell,
crush,
and brew herbs.
Once the sun sets,
you can make a bowl
of terrible noodles for her.
After that, my daughter
will reprimand you
while she finishes the noodles.
You will
feel embarrassed over it.
The next morning,
you'll go and buy osmanthus cakes for her.
Don't you think
that's pretty nice?
I can't just make terrible noodles for her
for the rest of my life.
I'm sure you like it as well.
I can live in Nan'an City.
I can lead a peaceful life there.
But what about the members of Blood River?
If they are allowed to roam free across the martial world,
they'll eventually die
where no one can find them.
You're a responsible man.
Uncle Zhe, I believe
that you were once a responsible man as well.
After all, you're the former Kui.
And, you're from the main family.
You were supposed to inherit the title of Patriarch.
I guess so.
Back then,
I had lofty aspirations.
I merely wanted
to make my name known throughout the world.
I wanted to fight for the world's number one title.
What happened after that?
After that,
I found love.
Since then, I have only wished
to leave the martial world
and lead a secluded life with her.
Blood River,
and the martial world,
none of them was as enticing as
watching a sky full of stars with her.
You're inferior
to me.
It seems like
I'm the best man
in the world.
Fadog,
what are you doing?
This should be the Divine-Demon Nirvana Art.
Rumor has it
that when one
has sustained grave injuries,
they can exchange their life for another.
Although it has been modified,
and the user won't die from it,
the user
will receive a serious backlash.
Uncle Zhe has truly given his all
for Su Muyu's sake.
I heard that Tianqi City hasn't been peaceful
recently.
Assassins attacked Flying Tiger General's Residence at night.
It was quite the commotion.
Dian Ye?
Who has he offended?
I have
no idea.
I think
it's some martial artists.
Martial artists, huh?
If that's the case,
shouldn't we ask Ruofeng about it?
It seems those martial artists
are Prince of Langya's acquaintances.
Martial artists like them
actually dared to attack a general
in Tianqi, huh?
They're too bold for their own good.
Relay my order to Dian Ye.
I'm granting him permission
to conduct a citywide manhunt for the assassins.
He can dispatch as many of the elite troops under him.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Now, I've reached the ninth level
of Hell Palm.
It feels as if the vast world
is but the size of my palm now.
By the way, old man,
were you unable
to reach the ninth level of Hell Palm
even after all these years?
The Hell Palm the Three Families of Tianqi practices
is different from the one
you guys are practicing.
The arts and manuals we have
are incomplete.
We can only reach the eighth level at most.
Even if you and I were on the same level,
I will be inferior to you.
I see.
I thought
you were merely ungifted.
I suppose that's correct as well.
But Patriarch,
do you know why
the Three Families of Tianqi
only have incomplete arts
and manuals?
Please tell me about it.
It's because Hell Palm
is a sinister art.
Those who reach the highest level
will receive a serious backlash.
Therefore, the manuals
we had in Tianqi City
were modified.
We cannot utilize
all of their power.
As for those in Blood River,
the original copy was kept within your organization
in order to seek out more power.
Long time no see,
Patriarch.
Do you know
what happened when you were away
on your reclusive retreat?
I heard that my friends at Blood River
almost died.
The head of Su family almost died as well.
As for He-Yu Clinic,
it was almost leveled overnight.
Do you guys know
that I'm furious right now?
It's all because you all were messing around.
Messing around?
Sir Zhuo Qing,
say, what if I mess around
and kill the prince in front of me
with one blow?
Will you be able to stop me?
Such audacity!
If it were the past version of you,
there was no way you could achieve that.
However, if it's the current you we're talking about,
there's a 50% chance
you'll be able to take Yong's life.
Should I give it a try?
♪Like fate, winding with the tide♪
♪Who can ford this river of night?♪
♪Where's the far shore we chase all our lives?♪
♪Surrendering all hues for a glimmer of light♪
♪Through joy and sorrow♪
♪Still I can't let go♪
♪Longing keeps me awake at night♪
♪My heart no longer my own♪
♪No one can escape from love♪
♪How many hidden feelings♪
♪Sink in silence deep?♪
♪Searching through the endless nights♪
♪Struggling on the edge of love and pain♪
♪Shadows crossing shadows♪
♪Whose name hides in your eyes?♪
♪When the wind blows, ask not when I shall return♪
♪Ask not when I shall return♪
♪Like fate, winding with the tide♪
♪Who can ford this river of night?♪
♪Where's the far shore we chase all our lives?♪
♪Surrendering all hues for a glimmer of light♪
♪Through joy and sorrow♪
♪Still I can't let go♪
♪Longing keeps me awake at night♪
♪My heart no longer my own♪
♪No one can escape from love♪